simplicant.com 2019-05-28

# Privacy Policy - Modern Recruiting Software | Applicant Tracking System | Simplicant

Effective Date: August 8, 2018

## Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) outlines how Simplicant, Inc. (“Simplicant,” “we” or “us”) collects, uses, secures and discloses your information. This Privacy Policy governs your access of the Platform, regardless of how you access it, and by using our Platform you consent to the collection, transfer, processing, storage, disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. We abide by applicable laws and regulations and follow generally-accepted industry best practices for data security and privacy. We never sell or share personal information.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable person (e.g., name, address, email address, or phone number).

This Privacy Policy, and the consent described herein, does not apply to your interactions with our customers. Simplicant provides a platform that enables our customers to manage data that they collect subject to their own privacy policies. We only process data that is stored in our platform, as a data processor, under the direction of our customers, and we have no relationship with individuals whose personal data we process as per our customer's use of our platform and services.

1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND STORE

We may collect and store the following information, including Personal Information about you:

We collect personal information, including name, company name, job title, email address, phone number, when you request an online demo of our services, or request to receive product information through an online form on our website. We use this information to deliver the requested information about our Services.

Additionally, you may provide us with information such as job postings or candidate data, during account setup or ongoing use of the service, that will be uploaded to your account. Any information you upload into your account also constitutes as part of the information. When you visit our website www.simplicant.com or access our service, we automatically record information from your device such as its software, IP address, browser type, operating system, frequency of access, locale preferences and your activity while using our services. We also use “cookies”, “tags”, “scripts” to collect information, improve your experience and get a better understanding of your preferences.

When you use our services, our system automatically collects data from your Device and its software, called Log Data. This may include the device's IP address, browser type, how you landed on our website, pages you visit on our site, language preferences, your mobile carrier, date and timestamps, metadata, and other interactions with our services.

We use "cookies" to collect information when you interact with our services, and use this information to improve our platform and services. We may use cookies to save your login information for quicker logins to the service in future. We may also use "session ID cookies" to customize our service for your, to better understand how you use our services and to monitor aggregate usage on the service. You have control, through your browser by configuring its options, to disable cookies or to ask your permission before accepting a cookie from any website you visit including Simplicant. However, If you do not accept cookies, your ability to use some features or areas of our service may be limited.

2\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We may use the information that we collect, including Personal Information, for the following purposes:

To provide our service, to understand your needs and improve your experience about our service, to administer customer support, provide information about system updates, general announcements, billing information, additional product information.

To further improve your experience of our service, we may automatically collect and analyze data about your general usage of the Simplicant platform. The information includes but is not limited to; tracking pattern for frequently used features, frequency of system access, type of browser and operating system. The collected information will be aggregated and anonymized so as to not contain personally identifiable information.

We may also collect information (ourselves or using third party services) through your use of our services, which may sometimes correlate with personal information. We may use this information for the purposes described above and also to analyze the use of the service, for the purposes of technical administration, to improve our features and capabilities, and to verify that authorized users have access to the service. As of today, some of the services we use include New Relic and Google Analytics.

3\. HOW WE MAY DISCLOSE OR SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may share information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

We may share your Personal Information:

With our third-party service providers who help us provide, analyze, and improve the Service and to perform services on behalf of Simplicant and under obligations similar to those in this Privacy Policy.

We may also disclose your information: if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with applicable laws, in response to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena or warrant.

With Third Party Applications (“apps”). We allow for the optional integration with these apps and your use of them will be subject to their respective terms of service and privacy policies. Please note that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside apps or websites.

If we believe, in good faith, that sharing your Personal Information is appropriate or necessary to (i) take precautions against liability, (ii) protect ourselves or others from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses or activity, (iii) investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, (iv) to enforce the Simplicant Master Subscription Agreement or (v) to protect our legal or property rights.

During Business transfer. If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that transaction, but we will notify you of any change in control or use of your Personal Information, or if either become subject to a different Privacy Policy.

4\. MARKETING OPT OUT AND PREFERENCES

If you receive marketing or informational announcements from us, such emails will include the capability to unsubscribe from future such emails. Marketing announcements typically include information about our products and services. Transactional emails about your account or our Services are not considered “marketing” or “informational” communications.

5\. UPDATING OR DELETING YOUR INFORMATION

If you are a registered Simplicant user, you may review, update or delete your personal information from your Simplicant account. If you require any change, correction, or deletion of information collected by Simplicant customers, on whose behalf we process this information, you may submit a request directly to that entity to address your query. In some cases we may retain copies of your information if required by law. If you have questions about your information on our platform, contact us at privacy@simplicant.com and we will respond to your inquiry as soon as reasonably possible.

For individuals located in the EU region, kindly refer to the rights listed under Individual Data Protection Rights for more information about data correction or deletion.

6\. DATA RETENTION

If you wish to discontinue using the Platform or cancel your account, you may have your account deleted by sending a request to privacy@simplicant.com. We may retain information collected and processed on behalf of our customers for as long as needed to provide our Services. We retain and use this information as needed to enforce our terms and conditions, comply with legal obligations, and/or for the duration required by applicable laws. You may request to have your account deleted by sending an email request to “privacy@simplicant.com”. We will aim to delete your information as soon as possible once such a request is received. However, please note that there might be latency in deleting information from our servers and backed-up versions might exist after deletion.

7\. INDIVIDUAL DATA PROTECTION RIGHTS

You have the following data protection rights when using our Platform. The individual rights described below may be restricted a) if denial of access is required by law; b) if to protect our rights and properties; c) if rights or requests impact other's areas of privacy or is deemed impractical.

i) **Right to withdraw consent:** If you have provided consent for the processing of personal information, you can revoke your consent at any time. The withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing conducted prior to your withdrawal.

ii) **Right of access, rectification (correction), deletion (or “Right to be Forgotten”):** You may request to access a copy of your personal information, correct or update your personal information, or request to have your personal information erased from our records provided there is no overriding legitimate grounds for our processing.

iii) **Right to restriction:** You may ask to restrict the processing of your personal information stored in our systems.

iv) **Right to object to processing:** You may object to the processing of your personal information at any time if your information is being processed based on the consent you provided or our legitimate interest.

v) **Right to data portability:** You may request to have your personal information, being processed by us based on your consent or based on your contract with us, provided to you in a structured and standard format. The right to data portability is only applicable to the personal information provided by you to us.

Please note that any requests related to data protection rights described above should be directed to Simplicant customer (Data Controller) who holds, processed and stores your personal information in our systems. Simplicant (as Data processor) will not be able to respond directly to such requests and will refer such requests to the relevant customer (Data controller).

8\. HOW WE SECURE YOUR INFORMATION

The security of your information is important to Simplicant, and we have implemented industry standard practices to ensure that your personal data is safeguarded in compliance with this Privacy policy. However, electronic transmission over internet cannot be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Hence, absolute security cannot be warranted. To learn more about our security measures, visit [our security page.](https://www.simplicant.com/security-performance/)

9\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER OF INFORMATION

Unless you specifically request otherwise, your personal information collected through our standard services is stored, and processed in the United States where Simplicant is based. The data will be processed by us, in the United States where privacy laws and regulation may be different to other parts of the world. However, the protection mechanisms described in our Security policies remain applicable. By using this platform and our services, you agree to this privacy policy and you consent to the transfer of such information to the United States, and to the processing of such information as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

10\. POLICY FOR CHILDREN

Our services are not intended for, and we aim not to collect any personal information from children under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18. We will take immediate steps to delete such information, if we find out that such information has been inadvertently collected.

11\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Simplicant reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy as needed, and recommend you to review it periodically. We may provide a notice of change (for example, via email and/or a notice on our website and/or a notice inside the product interface), if the said changes are of significant nature. The updated policy will be effective when it is posted on this page. By continuing to use our services, after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the then-current Privacy Policy.

Addtionally, we may share supplementary information about the data collection, use and sharing practices of specific sections of our service.

12\. HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, feel free to contact us by emailing at privacy@simplicant.com
